Peek-a-boo!
躲猫猫
No, no, no, no, no.
别哭  别哭  别哭
I didn't mean to startle you, my little baby.
我不是故意吓你的  我的小宝贝
Hush, little vampire, don't say a word
小吸血鬼宝宝  别说话
Papa's gonna bite the head off a bird
爸爸会把鸟头咬下来
A-bitty goo-bah!
你个小不点儿
I want to kiss your tush.
我想亲亲你的小屁股
I want to kiss your tush!
亲亲小屁股
Nice, but maybe a little more square footage.
很好  但是面积要再大点
I want a lot of monsters here.
可以容纳更多妖怪
I'm gonna get you, little Mavis.
我来抓你啦  小梅维斯
I'm gonna get you!
我要抓住你啦
What out there?
外面有什么
Oh, we never go out there.
我们从不去外面
Ever.
永远不
"And then the monsters ran away and were forced into hiding.
后来妖怪们纷纷逃跑并躲起来
"But Harry the Human found them
但叫哈利的人类发现了他们
"and jumped out from under their bed."
从他们的床底下蹦出来
I'm scared!
我好怕怕
"And burned their clothes.
烧了他们的衣服
"And bit their toes!
咬他们的脚趾头
"And took their candy!"
还抢走了他们的糖果
Don't take my candy.
不要抢走我的糖果
Babyclaws, you don't need to be frightened.
小宝贝  别害怕
I promised your mommy I would protect you forever.
我答应过你妈咪会永远保护你
My beautiful May-vey
我美丽的梅维斯
Let me wipe all your poop away
我帮你把屁屁擦干净
Those humans are nas-tay
那帮人类都好坏坏
So with Daddy you will stay
还是和爸爸在一起吧
And if a human tries to harm you
要是有人想伤害你
I'll simply say
我就会
Because you're Daddy's girl
你是爸爸的小闺女
Daddy's girl
爸爸的小闺女
Just bend the legs and push off.
双腿弯曲  跳下来
Trust me, mouse.
相信我  小耗子
I can fly! I can fly!
我会飞啦  我会飞啦
Look at you!
看看你
Faster, baby! Faster!
再快点  宝贝  再快点
You got it, my little voodoo doll!
你成功了  我的小魔女
Excuse me, sir.
打扰了  先生
What? What?
怎么了  又怎么了
Ow. I'm Okay.
我没事
It's ready.
已经盖好了
Looks good.
看着不错
Only monsters can get in?
只有妖怪可以进来吗
Oh, absolutely.
当然了
It's hidden real nicely.
隐蔽地非常好
You got 400 acres of haunted forest in front of you.
前方有400英亩幽灵森林
You got the Land of the Undead on the perimeters.
周围是亡灵禁区
Any humans daring to even look over there
有谁敢朝那边多瞄一眼
will run away real quick.
都会仓皇而逃
But, of course, be smart.
但要切记
No bonfires, no firework shows.
不能有篝火  不要办烟火表演
Yeah, yeah, no, no. No fire, I get it, I get it.
不能有火  我知道了
It's time, my darling Martha.
终于好了  我亲爱的玛莎
The place we always talked about for Mavis.
我们以前常说要为梅维斯建造的地方
No one will ever harm her here.
这里永远没人能伤害她
《精灵旅社》
(现在)
(亡灵)
Yeah, it's a mess back there.
后面乱糟糟的
Welcome to Hotel Transylvania!
欢迎来到精灵旅社
Human-free since 1898.
始于1898年的无人类旅馆
Your safest destination.
你最安全的落脚点
Take an itinerary.
拿一份日程表
I have personally designed a spectacular schedule of events,
我亲自设计了许多精彩的活动
all leading to my daughter's birthday extravaganza tomorrow.
都是为我女儿明天的庆生盛会
We always look forward to coming every year, Count.
我们每年都盼着来呢  伯爵
We enjoy the safety so much.
我们特别青睐此处的安全性
Of course. That's why we built it.
那是当然  我们就是为此才建的旅馆
Yes, good evening.
晚上好
Thank you, Marty.
谢谢你  马蒂
You look pale, as well.
你看起来还是那么白
Sir, sir, sir!
先生  先生  先生
We have an urgent plumbing issue.
我们的管道有突发状况
Plumbing? On it.
管道  别急
Mr. Ghouligan!
胡立根先生
There is a clogged toilet in room 348.
348房间的厕所堵了
It's Okay. We all get stomach aches, Mr. Bigfoot.
没事  谁没个肚子疼  大脚怪先生
Hey, kids, reel it in.
孩子们  过来
You're only supposed to make Mom and Dad miserable.
别给爸妈惹麻烦
Now, now, is that any way to behave?
这样可不乖哦
This is a hotel, not a cemetery.
这是旅馆  不是墓地
Sorry, Uncle Drac.
对不起  德库拉叔叔
Drac! How are ya?
德库拉  你好吗
Wayne, my old friend!
韦恩  我的老朋友
Couldn't wait for this weekend.
我太期待这个周末了
Always great to be out of the shadows for a couple days.
离开那个阴森的地方几天也不错
The family looks beautiful.
你们家看起来其乐融融
Let me just clean up their filth.
他们弄脏的让我清理就行了
Housekeeping!
客房部
Frankie, my boy! Look at you!
弗兰克  孩子  看看你
Still traveling by mail, Mr. Cheapo, huh?
又把自己邮寄过来呢  抠门先生
It's not a money thing.
不是钱的问题
I have a plane phobia, okay?
我有飞机恐惧症  好吗
I mean, at any moment, those engines could catch...
我是说  那些引擎随时可能着
Fire! Yeah, yeah. "Fire bad."
火  没错  火是坏东西
We know.
我们知道
Augustus, Porridge Head, come on!
奥古斯都  浆糊脑子  有没有搞错
Does that look like Frankenstein's head?
那个像是弗兰克斯坦的头吗
Hey, Drac, buddy, what's going on with your cape there?
德库拉  老兄  你的披肩怎么了
What do you mean?
什么意思
Who pinched me?
谁掐了我
Guilty. You're irresistible.
抱歉  你太迷人了
Yes, very amusing, Invisible Man.
是啊  真好玩  隐形人
Hello. Great to "See" You.
你好  很高兴"看见"你
Never gets old.
老段子了
Missed me.
没打中
Missed me, missed me, missed me.
没打中  没打中  没打中
Okay, you win. Hold this bacon.
好吧  你赢了  拿着培根
Why am I holding bacon... Ahh!
干嘛要我拿着培根
No! Get 'em off!
不要  叫他们下去
Here comes the party!
派对我来也
Hello, Murray!
你好  默里
Drac, what's up, buddy?
德库拉  还好吗  老兄
The sand, Murray, the sand!
沙子  默里  沙子
Always with the sand.
总是风尘仆仆的
Wolfie! Wanda! Frank!
沃尔夫  旺达  弗兰克
I love this guy.
我喜欢这家伙
He always bringing it full tilt.
他总是声嘶力竭
You're looking skinny, too.
你看起来又瘦了
Now that you're just a head.
瘦得就剩一个头了
Okay, you'll pay for that.
我饶不了你
So what's up, Drac?
最近怎么样  德库拉
The hotel is looking off the hook.
旅馆现在运营得不错
Hey, guys, watch this.
各位  瞧好吧
By the way, you were right about those directions.
顺便说一句  你指对路了
Oh, good, good.
很好  很好
Yeah, I took the Tigris through the Nile,
真的  我从底格里斯河走到尼罗河
and there was absolutely no traffic.
一路畅行无阻
You're kidding me.
开什么玩笑
Right in my lobby?
我的大厅放屁
Drac, I swear, man, I don't run like that.
德库拉  我发誓  不是我放的
Housekeeping!
客房部
I was not the cause of that.
真的不是我
We're ready!
我们织好了
(生日快乐  梅维斯)
If only Martha were here to see this.
要是玛莎能看到就好了
She's always here, Wanda.
她一直在这儿  旺达
Okay, friends,
好了  朋友们
I am so glad you are here to celebrate.
很高兴你们能来此欢庆
Another birthday for my sweet little Mavis,
我可爱的小梅维斯的生日
and another successful year of refuge from them!
庆祝我们又成功躲过他们一年
These are recent human images our surveillance has uncovered.
这些是我们监测到的近期人类影像
They are getting fatter so as to overpower us.
他们越来越胖以便能打败我们
And they are wearing less clothing,
他们身上的衣服越穿越少
allowing more movement to strangle us
更能大展拳脚勒死我们
or cut open our heads and put candy in them.
或者砍掉我们的头当糖罐
But they will never find us here.
但他们永远不会发现我们在这儿
Evil villain, you will never win!
坏人  你们是不会得逞的
Okey-doke. The fun starts in 30 minutes.
好了  30分钟后好戏登台
Right now, I have to see my little girl.
现在  我得去看我的小闺女
She's not so little anymore!
她可不小了
Yes, she is!
不  她就是小
What's going on out there?
外面什么情况
Are we at the hotel?
我们到旅馆了吗
Frank, did you book us for a tandem massage?
弗兰克  你预约双人按摩了吗
Did you get us a table at Hunchback's?
在钟楼餐厅订位子了吗
Did you do anything?
你有没有在做事
You're welcome.
不客气
What's going on?
怎么回事
Dad, you said that when I turned 118,
爸爸  你说过等我到了118岁
I could go out into the world
就能像那些来旅馆的其他成人一样
like every other adult that gets to come and go from this hotel.
去外面的世界看看
"But, Mavey Wavey, it's not safe."
可是小梅  这不安全
Dad, 30 years ago, you promised.
爸爸  30年前你答应过我
I remember, we were both eating mice,
记得当时我们在吃老鼠
and you specifically said that you gave me your word.
你信誓旦旦地向我保证过
Do not disturb.
请勿打扰
Do not disturb. Do not disturb.
请勿打扰  请勿打扰
Do not disturb.
请勿打扰
Do not disturb. Do not disturb.
请勿打扰  请勿打扰
- Do not disturb. - Good morning, Your Eminence.
-请勿打扰  -早上好  阁下
Maid, clean up this room!
女佣  把这间打扫干净
It's you. Glad you could make it.
是你啊  很高兴你能来
- Is she up yet? - Oh, she's up.
-她起了吗  -起了
She's ready to go. And by "Go," I mean go.
她准备走了  我的意思是离家出走
As in, go check the world out.
是去外面的世界看看
What you gonna do? What you gonna say?
你怎么办  你会怎么说
I got it covered. Please, relax. Just do your job.
我都安排好了  你做好你的事就行了
Good morning, Mavey Wavey!
早上好  小梅
Happy birthday, my little mouse!
生日快乐  我的小耗子
Thank you, Dad.
谢谢  爸爸
I know it's my birthday.
我知道是我生日
I have so much fun planned.
我安排了好多好玩的
But first, we go catch some scorpions together,
但首先  我们要一起抓蝎子
just the two of us, yes, dead-ums?
就我们俩  怎么样
Dad, please, let me speak.
爸爸  听我说句话
There's something we have to talk about.
有些事我们得谈谈
You want to go out into the world. You can.
你想去外面的世界看看  去吧
I knew you were gonna say that.
我就知道你会这么说
But, Dad, you gave me your word,
可是  爸爸  你向我保证过
and you know that I know that a Dracula's word is sacred.
德库拉的承诺是神圣的
That our trust is the core of our...
我们之间的信任最重要
Wait, what?
等下  你刚说什么
I said you can go.
我说你可以离开
You're just playing with me.
你是在耍我吧
No, no, no, no. You're old enough to drive a hearse now,
不  不  你已经到了能开灵车的岁数
you're old enough to make your own choices.
你可以自己做决定了
You can go.
你可以离开
Holy rabies! Holy rabies!
我滴个兔乖乖
Stop.
先别走
Wait a second, sweetfangs.
等一下  小尖牙
Where are you going?
你要去哪儿
Oh, well, I'm going to Paradise,
我要去天堂
and this is just some stuff that I thought I would need.
这些是我觉得用得上的东西
Paradise?
天堂
Yeah, you know. It's that place out there where you and Mom met.
对啊  就是你和妈妈相遇的地方
Auntie Wanda says you two were just like, Zing!
旺达阿姨说你俩一见钟情
I don't know from "Zing."
我可不知道什么一见钟情
Where did you find that card?
你从哪儿找到的这张卡片
In one of your drawers.
你抽屉里
Why won't you ever tell me about how you met?
你怎么从来不给我讲你们是如何相识的
It's actually Hawaii.
其实是在夏威夷
Ha-what-what?
夏什么
Look, honey, I know you're excited,
宝贝  我知道你很激动
but everyone has gone to great lengths
可大家都不远万里
to come see you on your birthday.
来为你庆祝生日
I know. They always do.
我知道  他们一直如此
But aren't I getting a little old for these parties?
可我都这么大了  不适合办这种派对
I love them, but I really want to see new things.
我喜欢派对  但我真的想体验新事物
Maybe meet somebody my age.
想认识同龄人
Come on. No, no, don't do that.
拜托  别  别  别这样
Don't give me the pouty batface.
别摆出这副闷闷不乐的样子
Okay, there is a human village
好吧  就在离墓地不远的地方
just a little ways past the cemetery.
有个人类的村庄
You could go there and be back in, like, 30 minutes or so.
你可以去玩个三十分钟左右
It should be plenty for your first time.
对你第一次出行来说足够了
Well, it's not Ha-wee-wee,
好吧  虽然不是夏威威
but I guess it's still technically out there.
但怎么说也算外出了
Okay, okay, okay!
好  好  好
Thanks for trusting me.
谢谢你相信我
Of course, my little one.
当然了  我的小宝贝
I gave you my word.
我向你保证过的
Hey, honey!
你好  宝贝
- Look at this! - Hey, guys.
-看啊  -你们好
You excited about tomorrow?
对明天的到来很激动吧
Not as excited as I am right now.
我现在更激动
You're not gonna believe this,
说了你们也不信
but Dad is letting me go out on my own to see a human village!
爸爸让我一个人去人类的村庄看看
- What? - No!
-什么  -不行
Excuse me. Drac!
抱歉  德库拉
Have you lost it?
你疯了吗
Letting your own daughter out there
让你女儿外出
with those horrible humans you always tell us about?
和你常对我们说的恐怖人类待在一起
That's why you built this place.
你为此才建的这地方
They hate us. They're vicious.
他们恨我们  他们很恶毒
And they're very loud!
而且还吵死人了
Auntie Eunice, maybe they've changed.
尤妮斯阿姨  也许他们变了呢
I'm just gonna fly down the street and see how it goes.
我就飞到街边看看是什么样
Okay, honey, be safe.
好吧  宝贝  注意安全
Bring warm clothes and a sword.
带上暖和衣服还有剑
And look out for pitchforks.
当心干草叉
Don't you let anyone scoop your brains out, either.
别让人把你的你脑子挖出来
Maybe stay in the shadows.
或许待在暗处就好
It's more fun to just observe from under a house.
从地下室观察也挺有意思
Guys, guys. She can handle it.
各位  各位  她能处理
She's a Dracula, for Pete's sake.
她是个吸血鬼  看在上帝的份上
But seriously, watch out for fire.
但说真的  小心火焰
Fire bad.
火可不是好东西
Bye, everyone.
再见  各位
Drac,
德库拉
I can't believe how calm you are about her leaving.
不敢相信你对她的离开如此淡定
I'm proud of you.
真为你骄傲
Drac? Drac?
德库拉  德库拉
Where did Drac go?
德库拉跑哪儿去了
This is awesome!
太棒了
There's the cemetery, just like Dad said.
果然有个墓地  跟爸爸说的一样
Uh... Hello?
有人吗
Anybody out there?
有人在吗
- Vampire. - Bite toes!
-吸血鬼  -咬脚趾
Hi, humans.
你们好  人类
Everything Okay? My name is Mavis Dracula, and I...
没事吧  我叫梅维斯·德库拉  我...
Vampire.
吸血鬼
- Burn clothes. - Burn my clothes?
-烧衣服  -烧我的衣服吗
- Really? - Vampire!
-真的吗  -吸血鬼
- We take your candy. - Candy!
-我们要抢走你的糖果  -糖果
I'm friendly. I really am.
我没有恶意  真的
- Calm down, now. - Candy.
-冷静一下  -糖果
I just wanted to say hi.
我就是想打个招呼
Please. I've never hurt anyone.
拜托  我从未伤害过人
I'm homeschooled.
我都在家自修
Is that garlic?
那是大蒜吗
Holy rabies, you're on fire.
我滴个兔乖乖  你们着火了
Can I do anything? Can I help you?
我能做什么  能帮你们吗
Dad was right.
爸爸说得没错
It worked.
这招管用了
Now my baby will be safe forever.
这下我的宝贝永远安全了
All right, everybody, get back to work now.
好了  各位  马上回去干活
You don't need a mannequin.
不要拿模特
Leave the mannequin here. Come on.
把服装放下  快点儿
Where you been?
你去哪儿了
Why you sneaking around?
你干嘛鬼鬼祟祟的
Quiet.
安静
Sweetheart, have you returned so soon?
亲爱的  你怎么这么快就回来了
Oh. Come in, Dad.
进来吧  爸爸
How'd it go? How was the big world?
好玩吗  外面的世界怎么样啊
How was it out there?
外面怎么样啊
It was okay, Dad.
还行吧  爸爸
What? What's the matter?
怎么了  发生什么事了
Dad, you were right.
爸爸  你说得对
Humans are awful.
人类太可怕了
They were everything you said.
跟你说的一模一样
- They wanted to bite my toes. - Your toes?
-他们要咬我的脚趾  -你的脚趾
And they had garlic on bread.
他们还往面包上放大蒜
What? Look at me.
什么  你看我
I'm getting goose bumps, I'm so scared.
我都起鸡皮疙瘩了  我好害怕
I'm so sorry, sweetheart.
我很抱歉  亲爱的
I hate that you had to see that.
很抱歉让你经历这些
I'm so sorry I doubted you.
对不起我不该怀疑你
I'll never leave here again.
我再也不离开这儿了
Okay. Okay.
没事了  没事了
Look, Daddy's going to make you the bestest birthday ever.
爸爸会给你过一个最棒的生日
Look what I brought you.
看我给你带了什么
Your wormcakes.
你的虫虫蛋糕
Don't be sad anymore.
别不高兴了
Remember,
别忘了
this is the year we open Mommy's present for you.
今年我们要打开妈妈给你的礼物
What did she get me?
她给了我什么
We'll see.
到时候就知道了
She said never to open until you're 118.
她说在你118岁之前不能打开
We've waited this long.
我们都等了那么久了
You eat your wormcakes.
吃你的虫虫蛋糕吧
You come down whenever you're ready, honey.
什么时候准备好了就下来  宝贝
What did you do?
你做了什么
What I had to.
做我该做的
She'll thank me one day.
有朝一日她会感激我的
Yeah, that's what the guy who shrunk my head said.
是啊  把我头缩小的人也这么说
Yes, what do you want, a cookie?
干得不错  你想要什么  点心吗
You did all right, man.
做得好  伙计
Move on already.
离开这儿
Yeah.
就这儿了
Vampire! Vampire!
吸血鬼  吸血鬼
A human.
人类
Who are you? And how did you find this place?
你是谁  你是怎么发现这的
Oh, I'm Jonathan.
我叫乔纳森
And I was just mountain climbing with some dudes,
我和一些朋友来登山
and heard this story about a spooky forest.
然后听到幽灵森林的传说
And who's not going to go into a spooky forest, right?
有谁不想去幽灵森林  你说是吧
So, then I see these goofy-looking dudes on fire.
后来我看到这些着火的傻家伙
And I just kind of followed them to this, like, amazing castle.
就尾随他们来到这座神奇的城堡
But, of course, be smart.
但要切记
No bonfires, no firework shows.
不能有篝火  不能办烟火表演
- How many of you are there? - Just me.
-你们有多少人  -就我一个
I like to hit it alone.
我喜欢独来独往
You meet so many awesome people in the youth hostels.
在青年旅社能遇到很多厉害的人
Hey, speaking of awesome, that cape thing is killing it.
说到厉害  这件披肩好拉风
Is there, like, a costume party here?
这在举行化装舞会吗
What have I done?
我都干了什么
This is all my fault.
都怪我
You have to leave.
你得离开这里
- Oh, no. - Excuse me.
-糟了  -不好意思
One of your piranhas in the lake is very rude.
你湖里的食人鱼真是粗鲁
He ate my sister-in-law.
他把我小姑给吃了
Be right with you.
我马上回来处理
Mr. Dracula, we asked for a room with a view of the pool.
德库拉先生  我们要面向泳池的房间
The room's fine. We want to book a massage.
房间不错  我们要预约按摩
Yes, Swedish. Shiatsu.
是啊  瑞典指压按摩
Aromatherapy. Lower back.
精油按摩  放松下背部
Do you have hot-stone? We want a massage.
你这里有热石吗  我们想按摩一下
- I'll get back to you, Mr. Hydraberg. - I hope so.
-我晚点回来处理  多头先生  -但愿如此
I doubt it. See that you do.
我表示怀疑  等你处理
That's Ms. Hydraberg. Thanks.
我是多头小姐  谢谢
- Yes, nice to see you. - Dude, seriously, what's up?
-是啊  很高兴见到你  -老兄  你到底怎么了
It's kind of funky to breathe under here.
这个聚会太给力了
Drac. Drac. How'd it go with Mavey?
德库拉  德库拉  小梅近来如何
Where'd you go?
你要去哪儿
This room's kind of small for a big castle.
城堡这么大  房间却这么小
No bed, but check out these awesome dustpans they give you.
连床也没有  但这个簸箕真酷
Quiet, you fool.
闭嘴  你个白痴
What weapons are you keeping in this container?
你包里装了什么武器
Your pitchforks?
干草叉
I can't breathe.
我无法呼吸了
It's killing me.
这味道熏死我了
Yeah, definitely due for a fluff and fold.
是啊  是该洗了
What is this?
这是什么
A torture device?
是刑具吗
A secret mind controller?
神秘的大脑控制器吗
You won't read my thoughts.
你看不到我的想法
I won't let you.
我不会给你这个机会
Dude, it's just music.
大哥  音乐播放器而已
Here, try it.
戴上试试
It's taking my soul!
我的魂都快被吸走了
What? It's a good jam. Don't be a grandpa.
什么  这是即兴演奏  别那么老土
You need to go.
你得离开这里
No human has ever entered this castle.
从未有人类进入这城堡
And if someone should see you,
如果你被人看见
the safety of the hotel, the sanctuary,
就再没人敢来这个旅馆了
no one would ever come again.
避难所将不复存在
Yeah, go for it.
好啊  接着说
"Ever come again!"
再没人敢来
I love your Dracula voice. It's so over the top.
我喜欢你的声音  很像德库拉  学得超像
And Mavis, if she saw you,
还有梅维斯  如果她看见你
she would know that I lied. No!
我的谎话就被戳穿了  不行
Who's Mavis? Is this her room?
谁是梅维斯  这是她的房间吗
I'm good with a roommate.
我不介意和人同住
I had six brothers growing up, so I could totally share.
我家一共兄弟六人  我很懂得分享
I can't kill him.
我也不能杀了他
It would set monsters back hundreds of years.
那会让妖怪的文明倒退几百年
One time, in Hamburg, I roomed with this dude
有一次我在汉堡和人同住
who I caught stealing my shampoo.
我抓到那人偷我的洗发水
I said, "Whoa, man," And
我说  住手  结果
he threw a flower pot at me, but he was cool.
他朝我扔来一个花盆  但他人还不错
What are you babbling about?
你瞎唠叨什么呢
What?
什么
Check out these awesome costumes.
看这些戏服多棒啊
Costumes.
戏服
What's this? Sorry, man. I just can't be without my backpack.
这是什么  抱歉  我不能丢下背包
You know, everything I own's in there.
我所有家当都在里面  不能离身
It'll be right here.
就放在这
Okay, I just... I love my backpack.
好吧  我只是太爱我的背包了
What are you doing?
你在干什么
What are you... What are you doing to my hair?
你这是  你要对我的头发做什么
Stop. Wait, that tickles.
住手  等等  痒死了
Come on, man.
别闹了
Check it out. I'm a Franken-homie.
快看啊  我是科学怪人
Yes, hello. Look at me!
大家好  看看我啊
This is totally normal, not a problem here.
一切正常  什么事也没有
This is just a monster with me.
不过是我身边的一个怪物
Man, everybody stepped it up tonight.
大家今晚都盛装打扮啊
Wait, why are we going to the front door? Are we leaving?
等等  我们为什么去门口  要走了吗
Bonjour,Dracula!
早安  德库拉
Sniffy. What's going on?
你好  大鼻子
Not right now, Quasimodo.
现在不是时候  加西莫多
What?
什么
No. Don't be absurd.
不可能  别胡说
It's not a human, but Monsieur Dracula.
他不是人类  他是德库拉先生
How ridiculous. It's me.
真好笑  是我啦
Monsieur.
先生
- The devilled lizard fingers. - Devilled lizard fingers?
-这是芥末蜥蜴趾  -芥末蜥蜴趾
I asked for spleens-in-blankets.
我让你做的是脾脏卷
You ugly fool! I told you, he doesn't like
你个白痴  我跟你说过  他不喜欢
- the lizard fingers! - But you said...
-蜥蜴指  -可是你说
Check that costume out.
看看这身装扮
Seriously, I just have to ask you:
说真的  我很想问你
How are you pulling this off?
你是怎么做到的
I mean, it looks so real.
这造型太逼真了
Like, I could just put my hand right through...
好像我的手指都能穿过去
What do you think you're doing?
你在干什么
She's real. You're real!
她是真的骷髅  你也是
Yeah, and I'll give you a real beating.
是啊  我还会真的揍你一顿
Keep your hands out of my wife!
别用你的脏手碰我老婆
No.
别别
Honey, I just didn't know where you were.
亲爱的  我不知道你在哪儿
We thought you were still out.
我们都以为你还在外面
No. I don't know why I ever wanted to leave.
不  我都不知道自己为什么非要出去
The humans are so boring.
人类真无聊
Mavis, honey, are you all right?
梅维斯  宝贝  你没事吧
Yeah, I think so. That was weird.
我没事  真是奇怪
My head hurts.
我头好疼
- Who is that? - Who is what?
-那个人是谁  -什么人
That.
那个啊
That is nobody.
没有什么人
- Seriously, Dad? - "Dad"?
-别开玩笑了  爸爸  -爸爸
Yeah, I know, Dracula's daughter. Everyone freaks out at first.
是啊  德库拉的女儿  谁都会被吓到
Dracula?
德库拉
Okay, we got to go.
好了  我们得走了
Please don't kill me. I'm so young.
求你别杀我  我还这么年轻
I have so many places I want to see.
我还有许多地方没去过
I've got tickets to six Dave Matthews Band concerts.
我都买了戴夫·马休斯乐队演唱会的票
I'm getting out of here.
我要出去
Shut up already.
把嘴闭上
It's impossible for me to think with all your noise.
你总嚷嚷我没法思考
Sorry, Glen. Go back to sleep.
抱歉  格伦  接着睡吧
Wait. Aren't you going to suck my blood?
等等  你是要吸我的血吗
Classic human paranoia.
典型的人类妄想症
Human blood is so fatty, and you never know where it's been.
人类都血脂高  不知道血里有什么疾病
So, Dracula doesn't drink blood?
那德库拉不吸血吗
No, I use a blood substitute.
不  我有替代品
Either Near Blood or Blood Beaters.
人造血还有混合剂什么的
You can't tell the difference.
喝起来没什么区别
So, you're, like, the real Count Dracula.
你是真的德库拉伯爵
Like, "I'm Dracula. Bleh, bleh-bleh."
你是不是常说  我是德库拉  吓死你
I've never said that in my life. Bleh, bleh-bleh
我这辈子都没那么说过话  吓死你
I don't know where that comes from.
都不知道人们怎么杜撰的
Can I just ask, what exactly is this place?
我能问这到底是什么地方吗
What is this place?
这是什么地方
It's a place I built for all those monsters out there,
这是我为外面那些怪物所建的避难所
lurking in the shadows, hiding from the persecution of humankind.
使他们能隐藏在黑暗中  躲避人类的迫害
A place for them and their families to come to and be themselves.
这里能让他们和家人休闲娱乐
A place void of torches, pitchforks, angry mobs.
这里没有火把  干草叉和愤怒的人群
A place of peace, relaxation
一个远离纷争
and tranquility.
宁静祥和的地方
Cool. So, it's like a hotel for monsters?
不错嘛  这么说这里是怪物旅店咯
Yes, exactly. "A hotel for monsters." Way to sum it up.
没错  怪物旅店  可以这么说
Okay, hop on my back. We're leaving.
好了  爬到我背上  咱们出发
You're a bat now.
你变成蝙蝠了
I always wanted to fly. What's it like?
我做梦都想飞  那是什么感觉
This is insane. Wait. Wait, I want to stay.
太疯狂了  等等  等等  我想留下
Can Frankenstein sign my costume?
能让弗兰克斯坦在我衣服上给我签个名吗
Can I meet the Invisible Man?
我能去看看隐形人吗
If I stuck my hand in the Invisible Man's mouth,
如果我把手放到隐形人嘴里
would it disappear?
手会消失吗
Mavey! What are you doing, my sweet little blood orange?
小梅  我的小甜心  你怎么来了
Our friend was just leaving.
我们的朋友正要走呢
Yeah, he was flying me out the window.
是啊  他把我撵出窗外
This guy, he's so funny.
这孩子  真幽默
Look, you have something on your face.
看啊  你脸上有点东西
Play along if you ever want to see your precious backpack.
敢乱说话就别指望再见到你的宝贝背包
So, wait, you didn't
等等  你变成蝙蝠时
have any clothes on when you were a bat?
身上什么衣服都不穿吗
Or were they bat-sized?
还是穿特制蝙蝠衫
Who exactly is that?
他到底是谁
Honeybat.
小宝贝
You see, it's your birthday.
因为你生日
And you know I want you to have the bestest,
我要让你过一个最棒的
specialest party of your life.
最特别的生日
So, We... I needed some help.
所以我需要帮手
You needed help?
你还需要帮手
Look, I am very good, but I thought it would be
我一个人是没问题  但我想如果由
even more bestest, specialest if
和你年龄相仿的人来策划派对
someone closer to your age helped plan the party.
就会让这个生日更完美  更特别
- You're my age? - Sure.
-你和我年龄相仿  -当然
How old are you?
你多大了
118.
118岁
One hundred and...
一百多
Yeah, I'm 121.
是啊  我121岁
Really?
真的吗
You see? Everything is very, very normal.
看到了吧  一切都再正常不过了
I'm throwing a party, and he's helping.
我要办派对  而他来帮忙
- Sir, there's an emergency. - Not now.
-伯爵  有紧急情况  -等会儿再说
Can't you see we're in the middle of something very normal here?
你没看见我们正在讨论正常的事吗
Wait, what's going on here?
等等  到底怎么了
There's an emergency in your precious hotel,
你最宝贝的旅馆出现紧急情况
and you're not running to fix it?
你却没马上跑去处理
Why? Is it because of him?
为什么  是因为他吗
Look at my face.
看我的表情
No, precious bones, it's not because of him.
不是  亲爱的  当然不是因为他
Good. Then go check on the emergency, and I'll keep him company.
很好  那你去处理吧  我来陪他
- No! Anything but that! - What?
-不行  绝对不行  -什么
I mean, because he needs time to plan.
因为他需要时间计划
And if you're keeping him company, then he's not planning.
如果你陪他玩  他就没时间策划了
He is company-keeping,
他比较贪玩
and then the plan, it's... It doesn't get planned.
该做的事情就没时间做了
- Good one. - Shut up!
-真能瞎编  -闭嘴
Okay. So, maybe if you're not planning later, we can hang out.
好吧  也许等你策划完我们能一起玩
- Sounds good. - Yes. You hear that?
-好主意  -好的  你听到了吗
It sounds good.
他答应了
So you will hang out. See you later, my honey. Lovely.
你们能出去玩  一会儿见  亲爱的小宝贝
Okay, you're not hanging out.
好了  你不能跟她玩
Because you are leaving.
因为你要走了
But the opposite, you said.
可你刚刚答应她了
But, sir, the emergency.
伯爵  紧急情况还没处理
Follow me.
跟我来
Boy, that kid smelt.
天啊  这孩子熏死人了
Where are we going?
我们要去哪儿
Just getting rid of you
走秘密通道把你赶出去
through a secret tunnel so she does not see us.
这样她就看不见我们了
So, can I ask you a question?
我能问你个问题吗
Is that real, about the garlic thing?
你真的怕大蒜吗
Yes, I cannot have it. My throat swells.
是啊  我不能吃  吃了嗓子会肿
Wooden stake to the heart?
那用木桩钉心脏呢
Yeah, who wouldn't that kill?
也怕  那样谁都会死
Here we go.
到了
I'm sorry. I'm a little lost.
抱歉  我有点迷路
Yes, I know it's your honeymoon. I apologize.
我知道你们在度蜜月  抱歉
Go back to doing what you were doing.
你们继续
I'm not down here much.
我不常下来
It's meant to be an exit if humans ever invade.
这里是人类入侵时的紧急出口
So, I'm, like, the first human here?
这么说  我是第一个来这里的人类
That's really cool.
太酷了
Oh, boy.
我的天啊
I think this is it.
可算找到了
- What's happening? - I'm terribly sorry.
-出了什么事  -我非常抱歉
- My mistake. - What is wrong with you people?
-是我的错  -你们到底想干什么
This place is amazing.
这地方棒极了
Okay, I could really use some silence right now.
行了  你就别废话了
All right, third time's a...
好了  第三次应该成功了
Drac.
德库拉
Yes, Frankie?
是我  弗兰克
Buddy, what you been doing?
哥们儿  你来干嘛
Don't move.
站着别动
Never mind that. What you been doing?
没什么事  你们在干什么
We wanted to practice our big number for Mavis's party,
我们在为梅维斯的派对排练节目
and then these losers wouldn't get off the bandstand.
这帮废物就霸着演奏台不放了
Okay. Put down Zombie Mozart,
好了  赶快把僵尸莫扎特
Bach and Beethoven this instant.
巴赫和贝多芬放下
Did you get to rehearse at all, Zombie Beethoven?
僵尸贝多芬  你排练了吗
Listen, Drac, we wanted to play something, like old times.
德库拉  我们想怀旧一番  表演些老节目
We even thought maybe you'd sing with us.
我们甚至想让你和我们合唱
Come on, fellas. You know
得了  伙计们  你们知道
that I haven't sung in public since Martha.
自从玛莎去世后  我就再没当众表演过
Yeah, but we just thought how much,
是啊  但我们想
you know, Mavis would love it.
梅维斯一定会非常喜欢的
I said no!
我说不行
Don't ask me again!
别再问我了
Okay. Now, let's hug the zombies. Let's all make up.
好了  拥抱一下僵尸们  大家和好吧
- He really scared you. - I wasn't scared.
-他真的吓着你了吧  -我不害怕
I was being polite, okay?
我不过是表示礼貌  懂吗
What are you doing here? I thought you were planning.
你在这里干嘛  我以为你在策划派对
I never caught your name.
我还不知道你的名字
My name's Mavis.
我叫梅维斯
Mavis? That's a pretty neat name.
梅维斯  这名字真好听
Yeah, my mom picked it.
是啊  是我妈妈起的
So, are you going to tell me your name?
那你叫什么名字呢
Me? My name? Good question.
我  我的名字  问得好
Obviously, I'm Frankenstein.
显然  我是弗兰克斯坦
No, you're not. Frankenstein is my uncle over there.
不可能  弗兰克斯坦是我叔叔  就在那边
The gentleman hugging Zombie Mozart.
正在拥抱僵尸莫扎特
Right. Of course, he's your uncle.
是啊  当然  他是你叔叔
See, I'm not "The" Frankenstein.
我不是那个弗兰克斯坦
I'm his cousin, Johnnystein.
我是他表弟  强尼斯坦
- Johnnystein? - Mavis.
-强尼斯坦  -梅维斯
Who is that?
那是谁
Are these monsters going to kill me?
这些怪物会杀了我吗
Not as long as they think you're a monster.
只要他们认为你是同类就不会杀你
That's kind of racist.
简直是种族歧视
We'll talk later.
这个咱们回头再聊
- Is he making fun of me? - No, no.
-他这是取笑我吗  -不  不
Of course he's not, because he's...
他当然不是  因为他是
he's your cousin, Johnnystein.
你的表弟  强尼斯坦
Yes, yes, yes.
是啊  没错
I don't have no cousin.
我没有表兄弟
No, no, you do. He's your sixth cousin, three times removed.
不不  你有  他是你三代以外的第六位表弟
On your right arm's side.
是你右手那边的亲戚
You have a cousin?
你还有个表弟
Frank, if your arm could talk,
弗兰克  如果你的手臂能说话
he would tell you that the
他会告诉你
original owner of your arm had a brother.
你手臂的原始主人有位兄弟
Who married a woman.
他娶了一个女人
Who was... for strangling a pig.
他杀死了一头猪
I have pig-strangling blood in my arm?
我的胳膊里有杀猪的血统吗
That's kind of cool.
感觉真酷
Cuz, great to meet you.
表弟  很高兴见到你
So, what brings you here, Johnny?
什么风把你吹来了  强尼
- What was that? - Sorry.
-那是什么  -抱歉
I should really clear my throat before I speak.
我说话前应该清清喉咙弄点动静出来
Anyway, what brings you here?
什么风把你吹来了
Party planner.
我是派对策划人
Yes, I have recruited Mr.
没错  是我聘请
Stein here to help me with Mavis's birthday party.
斯坦先生帮我策划梅维斯的生日派对
Wait a minute, you asked someone to help you?
等一下  你请人帮忙
Captain Control Freak?
你可是出名的控制狂
It's Count...
我是伯爵
And yes, I thought having a Mavis contemporary would be useful.
没错  我觉得请个和梅维斯同龄的人会更好
Yeah, he totally needed a fresher perspective.
是啊  他确实需要点新思路
Okay, Johnny, Mr. Tight Coffin over here
好了  强尼  那位老古董先生
was planning to have these powdered lame-os play at the party.
正打算让这群废物在派对上表演呢
So, anyways, we thought we could liven things up a bit.
不管怎样  我们觉得可以让场面生动一点
You all play? Let's check you guys out!
你们全都出场吗  让我们开开眼吧
Girl
姑娘
I can't believe it's your big night.
真不敢相信  今晚是你的大日子
Seems like only yesterday you were eating mosquitoes
你吃蚊子的样子  仿佛就在昨天
But now you're eating frogs and mice.
但现在你已经能吃青蛙和老鼠
Scarfing them down like Doritos
把它们抽筋扒皮  烧烤烹炸
Tell me.
姑娘  告诉我
Where did the time go, girl?
为何时光飞逝
Hold on, guys.
大家稍等一下
Stop.
停
That's cute, but kind of old school.
是很可爱  但有点过时了
Yes, thank you, Johnny.
是的  谢谢  强尼
You got to totally tempo things up.
你们得来点快节奏的
Here, let me show you.
看我给你们示范下
Werewolf man, give me a jam!
狼人大叔  来段即兴演奏
2, 3, 4
2  3  4
Vampire girl with the fangy fangs.
吸血鬼女孩  牙齿尖尖
Hair real cute with the bangy bangs.
发型可爱  刘海妩媚
Little princess gonna be a queen.
小公主即将变成女王
Legal bat lady turning 118.
蝙蝠女士芳龄118岁
118! Say 118!
118岁  说118岁
118!
118岁
Yeah! Stage dive!
来个台扑
Awesome.
真棒
I am so blown away right now.
我完全被征服了
I think my cuz is gonna make this
我觉得我表弟能策划出
the best party ever!
史上最棒的派对
Yeah! Maybe he can find a way to get me some chicks.
没错  也许他还能替我勾到妹子
We should do a dance contest!
我们该举办舞林大会
We're not doing any of that.
什么都不许做
We've got to stay on schedule, all right?
一切按照计划来  懂吗
All right, Dad, all right.
好的  爸爸  没问题
- Johnny, you're coming, too. - I don't know.
-强尼  你也要参加  -我不知道
- Is it cool with Dracula? - Johnny, come with us.
-德库拉会同意吗  -强尼  来吧
N-27.
N27
G-61.
G61
Bingo! Bingo!
中了  我中了
How dare you.
你吃了豹子胆
Do you know what doctor made me?
你知道我是哪位医生做的吗
I didn't do that.
不是我吃的
Circles?
圆圈
Fly?
苍蝇
Hands? Film.
手  电影
Vomit. The Vomit?
呕吐  呕吐物
- The Throw Up. - No. That wasn't a clue.
-呕吐  -这个不是让你们猜的
Nothing?
空无一物
Emptiness? Glasses?
空虚  眼镜
Glasses? Glasses shaking?
眼镜  晃眼镜
Glasses shaking sideways!
眼镜斜着晃
Through The Looking-Glass?
透过眼镜看
I stink at this.
猜得我都恶心了
I didn't do that.
不是我吃的
And pull it back. And up. And push.
手收回  举臂  向前推
And twist. And back.
转体  收回
And up. And twist.
举臂  收回
And push.
向前推
No. Don't copy that.
不  这个别学
And back. And up. And twist.
收回  举臂  转体
Let me get a bubonic moose nose omelet
我要一个淋巴腺麋鹿鼻子蛋卷
with cockroach paste and mouse jelly.
要加蟑螂酱和老鼠果冻
And with egg whites.
加蛋清
Bonjour, Monsieur Dracula!
早安  德库拉先生
May I make you an omelet?
要给您做个蛋卷吗
No, no, no, no. I'm not hungry.
不  不用  我不饿
What? Esmeralda, you smell it again?
什么  艾斯梅拉达  你又闻见人类的味道了
- Human? - I am hungry.
-人类  -我饿了
Johnny, you've been to the Taj Mahal?
强尼  你去过泰姬陵吗
Come on. No monster's been to the Taj.
算了吧  没有怪物能去泰姬陵
Man, I wish I could go there.
真希望我能去看看
You know what? I'll take 50 omelets.
告诉你  我要吃50个蛋卷
You heard the man! Make them!
听见了吧  快做
How did you deal with the mobs?
如果被人群围堵怎么办
Yeah, it does get pretty crazy in the summer.
是啊  夏天的确人超级多
But, you know, you just got to roll.
随机应变就好啦
He just rolls. That's cool that he rolls.
他能随机应变  真酷
Yes, yes, cool.
是呀  是呀  真酷
Look, love droppings, I brought
宝贝  我给你拿了
you a bagel with your favorite scream cheese.
你最爱吃的尖叫奶酪面包圈
Holy rabies. Thanks, Dad.
太棒了  谢谢  老爸
Johnny, try some scream cheese, it's awesome.
强尼  你也尝尝尖叫奶酪吧  超好吃
Cool.
真酷
But I'm scream cheese intolerant. So, polite pass.
但我对这东西过敏  还是你吃吧
Yes, of course you are.
对  你会过敏
Johnny, can we party-plan talk for a minute?
强尼  我们讨论一下派对的事情吧
What are you doing?
你干什么
If they find out you are human, they'll go bat poop!
如果他们发现你是人类  就乱套了
Relax. No one suspects anything.
别担心  没人怀疑
The only thing that looks
你老是这样给我说悄悄话
weird is how much whispering you're doing.
不让人怀疑才怪
Just wrap it up.
那你就快点走人
You will say you are going in the pool and act excited.
就说你想去游泳  表现得兴高采烈一点
And then you will say you hurt your back and you have to leave.
假装不小心闪着腰了  然后离开这里
Here come good times!
大家来欢乐一下吧
Oh, dudes. Oh, my back.
哎哟  我的背
I'm on your back!
我这就让你背
No, no. He said, "Oh, my back."
不  不  他是说  我的背
- Get on my back! - Let's do it.
-跳我背上来  -来吧
Here we go. Chicken fight! Push them off!
来啦  骑马打仗  放倒他们
Chicken fight!
骑马打仗
We got you, Johnny.
你跑不了  强尼
You're going down.
你死定了
Oh, yeah, we'll see, "Mavey Wavey."
看谁厉害  小梅
Okay, calm down with the fight chickens!
停  别玩儿骑马打仗了
Everyone, stop the roughhousing!
大家都停下来  别闹了
Frank, if you hurt yourself...
弗兰克  你要是摔伤了
I got it, honey.
别担心  亲爱的
The Stein boys are bred for this kind of thing.
科学怪人天生就是玩儿这个的
Geronimo!
杰罗尼莫
Kids, why'd you do that?
小兔崽子  你们干嘛脱他内裤
I was just in the pool.
我刚从游泳池出来
The water's cold.
水冷死了
Don't judge me!
别笑我
Johnny. Your makeup.
强尼  妆掉了
Your makeup!
妆掉了
Climb out. Now.
快给我出来
Oh, man.
不是吧
I guess the Count wanted to go for a swim.
原来伯爵也想游一圈呀
Cannonball!
深水炸弹
Oh, you messed up, baby. You messed up big-time.
小子  都给你搞砸了  弄得乱七八糟
I told you to take it down.
我让你消停点
You'll ruin my hotel if they find out.
要被他们发现还不把我家给拆了
Well, maybe you're just jealous
我看你是嫉妒吧
that people are finally having fun at this place.
看大家玩儿得这么开心
Oh, that? That was not fun.
是吗  那就叫开心吗
Everyone running,
大家都跟疯子似的跑来跑去
jumping, swimming with no order.
上窜下跳  乱游一气
That was the opposite of fun.
那才不叫开心
Do you even know what fun is?
你知道什么是开心吗
I invented fun!
开心是我发明的
Boy, the wrong people get to be immortal.
老天  怎么这么无聊的人会长生不死
Look at me.
看着我的眼睛
You remember nothing of this encounter.
忘记你在这里的所见所闻
You have no memory of this place or the monsters you met.
抹掉在这里的一切记忆
Now go and never return.
离开这里  永远不要再回来
Wait, never return to the hotel?
等一下  再也不能回到这个城堡吗
What? You were supposed to forget the hotel.
怎么回事  你本该忘掉这个城堡的
I just used my powers to erase your memory.
我在用魔法消除你的记忆
I looked straight into your eyes.
我直视你的眼睛
Oh, maybe it's the contact lenses.
或许是因为我带了隐形眼镜吧
The what?
什么东西
These little plasticky doodads that help me see better.
就是有这个塑料小玩意儿我才能看清
Here, let me just try and get them out real quick.
我给你摘下来看看
Oh, that is the most disgusting thing I've ever seen!
我从没看过这么恶心的东西
Almost got it.
就快拿下来了
Stop doing that. Please stop doing that!
别拿了  别拿了
Fingers away from the eyeballs! Enough!
手指头离眼珠子远点  够了
Listen to me. You are never to return here.
听好了  你再也不许来这儿
You are to stay away and never tell humans about this place.
离这远远的  不许对任何人提起
Or I will track you down and suck every ounce of blood
否则我会找到你  吸干你的血
from your body until you look like a deflated whoopee cushion!
就像一个泄了气的橡皮垫子
Be gone.
快走
Can't believe I'm leaving, man. That could have been so great!
真不相信我就要走了  多好玩的地方
Dude ruined everything. Suck my blood.
那家伙真扫兴  说什么吸干我的血
I should have just said, "I'm staying, old man!"
我当时应该说  我就不走  老顽固
Give him a Bruce Lee kick. Boom! Right in the...
给他一记李小龙式的回旋踢  直接踢中
Oh, my God. Count Dracula.
我的妈呀  德库拉伯爵
Please don't kill me. I'm leaving, I'm leaving.
求求你别杀我  我这就走  这就走
Follow me.
跟我来
Oh. No, no, Mavis, I can't.
不行  梅维斯  我不能跟你走
I have to leave.
我得马上离开这儿
- You sure? It'll be fun. - Okay.
-真要走吗  会很好玩哦  -好吧
He's not gonna see me, is he?
他不会发现我吧
Wow, would you look at the view from up here?
你不来看看这里的风景吗
You could almost see Budapest.
都快能看到布达佩斯了
Who-da-pest?
忽达佩斯
Is that near Ha-wi-fi?
离夏威尼近吗
Huh? Oh, you mean Hawaii. Yeah, that place is a knockout.
你是说夏威夷吧  是啊  那里美翻了
I just went to a music festival there.
我前不久刚去过那里的一个音乐狂欢节
A human music festival?
人类的音乐狂欢节
Uh, I believe so.
我想是的吧
So, did they all bite your toes
那他们有没有咬你脚趾头
and shove garlic bread in your face?
还往你脸上扔蒜蓉面包呀
No. Well, one dude took a bigger bite
没有  不过  有个家伙把我的
out of my energy bar than I expected,
能量棒咬去一大口
but I blame that on the heat.
但我不怪他  是氛围太热烈了
It's amazing. You've been everywhere.
真好  你什么地方都去过
Well, you know, what's the alternative?
不出去转转能怎样呢
Just staying at home, never exploring,
无非宅在家里  大门不出二门不迈
never seeing what's out there?
外面发生了什么都一无所知
I'm only gonna be 121 once, right?
一辈子也就一个121岁  不是吗
Got to live it.
要活得带劲一点
Yeah.
是呀
Oh, man. The sunrise from here must be amaz... Ow.
天呐  这里的日出肯定美翻了
Oh, I'm sorry.
抱歉
Man, you've probably never even seen a sunrise, have you?
你从来没看过日出  是吗
No, not really. Why?
没有  没看过  怎么了
Come on. I have an idea.
跟我来  我有个主意
Watch.
看吧
Didn't I tell you guys we'd have fun in here?
我跟你们说过在这儿很享受吧
Is this not the best?
最舒服了不是吗
Yeah, I'm working up a nice sweat.
是呀  我出了一身汗
When's that Johnny kid gonna be done party planning?
强尼那小子什么时候把派对策划好
- He's a great hang. - Yeah, he's an animal.
-他真有意思  -他就是个小怪兽
And it was so nice seeing
看到梅维斯和他那么投缘
Mavis laughing and hitting it off with him.
真是温馨
Who's hitting what off? Please.
什么投缘  拜托
Mavis could never be with someone of his kind.
梅维斯才不会喜欢他这样的呢
I'm sorry? "His kind"?
什么意思  他这种
You're saying our kind's not good enough for you,
你是说我们科学怪人配不上你们吗
"Your Lordship"?
伯爵大人
No, no, no! Frank,
不  不  不  弗兰克
I didn't... I meant that she wouldn't
我不是  我是说她才不会
be into someone with such red, curly hair.
喜欢红毛卷发的家伙呢
Uh, what's wrong with red, curly hair?
红毛卷发怎么了
Why are you getting upset?
你生哪门子气
I have red curly hair!
我就是红毛卷发
Well, how was I supposed to know that?
那我怎么知道
This is the most incredible thing I've ever seen.
这是我见过的最美的风景
Johnny?
强尼
Look, settle down, fellas.
冷静点  伙计们
This is all a moot point because Johnny, he left.
强尼人都走了  说这些也没意义
Wait a minute. He left?
等等  他走了
Yes. He decided he didn't like Mavis,
是的  他说他不喜欢梅维斯
or any of us.
也不喜欢我们
Hmm. I guess Johnny had second thoughts.
我想强尼改变主意了
I can't believe you stuck around, man. You don't get it.
你竟然敢回来  你是不是没听清楚
Bad things are coming your way.
你惨了
I got to get my thoughts together.
集中精力
Okay.
好吧
You see these tables?
看到那些桌子了
You can spend the entire day pulling them out
把它们拉出来摆好  你今天就干这个吧
and placing them, party planner.
派对策划者
Fantastic. I'm trapped here.
真英明  把我困在这里
Now I know how your daughter feels.
我算是理解你女儿了
Enough! Enough! Stop!
够了  够了  停
Go to a corner, you're in a timeout!
去墙角  面壁思过
Timeout? I'm a grown man!
面壁思过  我不是小孩子
Okay. Table 57, please move to position 23.
好啦  57号桌  去23号位置
- That is cool. - Face the wall.
-太酷了  -面壁
17 to 48. 16 to 47. 19 to 50.
17到48  16到47  19到50
- Awesomeness. - Just let me do my work.
-帅呆了  -别打扰我
29 to 35.
29到35
42 to 18. 10 to 44.
42到18  10到44
17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23.
17  18  19  20  21  22  23
39 to 24.
39到24
36 up!
36起
29 to 35.
29到35
31 to 19.
31到19
24 up!
24起
7 to 25. 14 to 30.
7到25  14到30
Where'd you go, grandpa?
你哪去了  老爷子
Don't freak out, gravity face.
别吓傻了  小白脸
Eat my dust, gray fangs!
追着我屁股跑吧  大尖牙
56 and 43, to my side.
56和43  左右护卫
Prepare to cry, Billy Backpack.
准备受虐吧  背包小子
That's how we do it! Half-pipe, baby!
来吧  你抓不到我
Whatever.
走着瞧
Yes. Keep smelling.
对  继续追踪
You catch the human, and then I will make human potpie!
抓到他  我就可以做人肉馅饼了
27, 45, 65, 76, 48
27  45  65  76  48
block his path.
堵住他的路
Block his path!
Oh, come on now, dude man!
你小子可以呀
Nice!
有两下子
I got you, buddy.
我来救你了  老兄
Do not disturb!
小点声
People trying to sleep here!
人家睡觉呢
Did you see that?
你看见没
Who is that guy, Sir Breaks-a-lot?
看见那家伙了吗  零件先生
Oh, boy, I have to say, that was fun. Okay?
天呐  我不得不说  太有趣了
The fun you were talking about earlier? Nailed it!
你之前不是说有趣吗  说对了
Johnny?
强尼
Quasimodo!
加西莫多(钟楼怪人)
Mavis? Why are you still up?
梅维斯  怎么还没睡
The sun is out.
太阳都出来了
It could kill you, my honeyguts.
阳光会灼伤你的  我的小宝贝
I couldn't sleep. Do you know where Johnny went?
我睡不着  你知道强尼去哪儿了吗
I don't know. He...
我不知道  他
Why do you want to know?
你为什么这么关心
- Do you like him? - What?
-你喜欢他吗  -说什么呢
Pfft, no. Come on, Dad.
才不呢  拜托  老爸
He's so weird and awkward.
他横冲直撞  呆头呆脑的
It's like, are you an idiot or do you know you're adorable?
你这个白痴你不知道你很可爱吗
Eh... Hold that.
稍等
Do you have a location on Quasimodo?
知道加西莫多在哪吗
Yes, sir.
知道  伯爵
They're heading through the lobby, towards the kitchen.
他们穿过大厅  去厨房了
I need them stopped immediately.
立即阻止他们
- Is that clear? - Yes, quite.
-听清楚了吗  -听清楚了
We are on it.
我们这就去
Ha-ha! Missed!
抓不着
What is the meaning of this? Let me pass!
你们什么意思  让我过去
Quasimodo Wilson, you are coming with us.
加西莫多·威尔逊  跟我们走一趟
Why did that hurt me?
我为什么会痛
Look, honey, there's no falling in love at your age.
宝贝  你这个年龄不适合谈恋爱
Mom was my age.
妈妈就是我这么大恋爱的
Eunice says Mom kissed you first,
尤妮斯说是妈妈主动亲的你
'cause you were too scared to make the first move.
因为你胆小不敢主动
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
是  是  是  是  是
Forget about me and Mom and kissing.
先不说我和你妈的初吻
Dad, at some point, I'm going to get married.
老爸  总有一天  我也要结婚
I can't be here forever.
我不可能在这儿待一辈子
What? Why not?
什么  为什么不
You're barely out of your training fangs.
你才刚换了牙
Quasi wins again!
我又赢了
When you bump with the hump, you land on your rump!
敢跟我作对  把你们摔个屁滚尿流
But why all the sudden interest?
怎么突然感兴趣了呢
Every time we used to talk about love, it was always,
每次我们说这个话题  你总说
"Ooh, Dad, that's gross,"
老爸  你真讨厌
and "Ooh, Dad, I don't want to know about that."
要么就是  老爸  我不想聊这个
I don't know.
我不知道
Sir, he made it into the kitchen.
伯爵  他到厨房了
He what?
你说什么
What do I pay you for?
我花钱要你干什么吃的
I'm sorry, honey. I have to go.
抱歉  宝贝  我得走了
He doesn't pay me.
他才没花钱
Before you kill me,
杀我之前
can I please talk to my backpack one more time?
能不能让我再看我的背包最后一眼
I don't want to leave anything unresolved.
我不想留下遗憾
Bonjour, Monsieur Dracula!
你好啊  德库拉先生
Shut your hump hole.
闭上你的臭嘴
Now you are helping him?
你是要救他吗
What is it with you and this human?
你为什么要护着人类
He is not human. He's a Stein!
他不是人类  是科学怪人一族
That's right, little man, I'm a Stein!
没错  矮冬瓜  我是科学怪人一族
If he is a monster,
如果他真是怪兽
let him scare Esmeralda!
让他吓唬艾斯梅拉达试试
The mouse?
那只老鼠吗
Without a doubt.
这还不好说
Okay. Here we go.
等着瞧吧
A human! A human!
有人类  有人类
Monsieur Dracula has brought a human into the...
德库拉先生把人类放进来了
Esmeralda, help me.
艾斯梅拉达  救我
Hey, thanks for saving me back there.
谢谢你救了我
That guy's crazy! Trying to eat me.
那家伙真是疯子  竟然想吃了我
That's only happened to me one other time.
这种事之前就遇到过一次
This weird dude at a Slipknot concert.
在活结乐队的一场演唱会上
There's something I need to show you.
我要给你看样东西
Hey, are we at a funeral right now?
难道是让我参加葬礼吗
Oh, wait, no, it's your bed.
不对  不  这是你的床
So creepy and cool.
真是酷毙了
Wow! I know her!
我知道她
I've seen that picture at the ruins of Lubov.
我在卢波遗址见过这幅画
That's my favorite castle.
那是我最爱的城堡
There's a whole legend around that lady.
还有一个关于她的传说
A legend?
传说
The Lady Lubov.
卢波魅影
The story is that a lonely Count met her by chance,
传说有个孤独的伯爵跟她偶然相遇
and they say that no two souls
他们发现彼此
were ever more meat for each other.
就是对方命中注定的另一半
Eventually, they settld down at Castle Lubov
最后他们在卢波定居下来
and had a child.
还有了个孩子
But then, a horre tragedy happened.
好景不长  灾难来临了
A fire started mysteriouy one night, and it killed both of them.
他们在一场神秘的大火中丧生
When I was at the castle, I could still feel their powerful love.
当我置身城堡  仍能感到那股爱的力量
They say it's as if a soul
就像人们说的那样
is still trapped in the ruins themselves.
似乎有灵魂萦绕着城堡
The legend is wrong.
传说是错的
It was only the wife that died.
只有那个妻子死了
And it was no mystery who killed her.
杀死她的不是什么神秘大火
She was killed by your kind!
而是你们人类
Vampire!
吸血鬼
Honey?
亲爱的
Go hide. I'll take care of this.
快躲起来  我来对付他们
Vampire!
吸血鬼
Martha!
玛莎
They are the real monster.
他们才是怪物
I built this place for my love,
我为我的爱人建造了这个城堡
to protect her child.
来保护我们的孩子
As a father, you do everything to keep your family safe,
一个父亲会尽其所能保护他的家人
even if you have to break their trust.
即便不得已欺骗他们
But now, Mavis has feelings for you.
但是  梅维斯喜欢你
What?
什么
I just...
我真
- Awesome. - It's all right.
-太好了  -没关系
You are a good one.
你很善良
If the world was different, maybe it would be possible.
如果世界不是这个样子  或许还有可能
Drac, this is the 21st century.
德库拉  现在是二十一世纪了
People aren't the same as they were back then.
人们已经不是过去的样子了
Can you tell me for certain that if we came out in the open,
你敢保证  如果我们身份暴露
everyone would accept us?
所有人都能接受我们吗
Everyone?
所有人
No. You're right.
不  你是对的
I'll go for good this time.
这次我会永远离开
You can just say I had some emergency,
你就说我有急事
or the gremlin lady ate me or something.
或是被鬼精灵吃掉了
No, no, no, no, no.
不  不  不  不  不
I don't want to ruin her birthday party.
我不想把她的生日派对搞砸
You can sneak out after it's all done.
等派对一结束  你悄悄离开就好
I'm sorry.
对不起
The last thing I wanted was to hurt her.
我不想伤害她
Or you.
也不想伤害你
You know, you're not the smoothest Frankenstein,
知道吗  你或许装不了最棒的科学怪人
but you'd make a great vampire.
但绝对能扮个完美的吸血鬼
For real?
真的吗
'Cause I think I kind of got your hypno-eyes down.
因为我也觉得能模仿你的记忆催眠
Oh, boy, here we go. Let me see it.
你小子又来了  快试试看
Beware! For you are in my power.
当心  你已经被我控制
I command you to be the werewolf man!
我命令你变成狼人
I have too many kids.
我孩子太多了
Someone scratch me, I have fleas.
他们老搔我  都长虱子了
'Cause he's a wolf, he'd get those.
狼人嘛  都长虱子
Yeah, no, don't explain it.
是吧  不  不能多嘴
It's not funny when you do that.
一解释就不好玩儿了
I didn't order a wake-up call.
我不需要叫醒服务
Count Dracula arranged it for all the rooms.
德库拉伯爵为每个房间都安排了
Where's the snooze button?
怎么关掉
There will be no snoozing. The party's today.
关不掉  今天有派对
Ooh, yeah, perfecto.
真舒服呀
Girl
宝贝
I can't believe it's your big night
真不敢相信终于等到今天
You ate your frogs, now the party's so right
青蛙是你的大餐  派对为你而办
Where did the time go, girl?
时间悄悄溜走  宝贝
And, girl, you used to suck a binky
宝贝  曾经的你天真纯白
Look at you now
如今婷婷玉立
You're sucking blood right out of the cow
尽情享受牛血的新鲜
You look beautiful.
你真美
Thanks. Thanks for the party.
谢谢  谢谢你办的派对
Yeah, you like my little touches?
是吗  你喜欢这样的场景吗
(巴黎)
(纽约  第五大道  中央公园)
(莫斯科)
(夏威夷)
It's amazing.
太赞了
Terrific party.
派对太棒了
You really outdid yourself, Drac.
真让我刮目相看  德库拉
Got to be the best one I've been to in 500 years.
这是五百年来我参加过的最好的派对
Sorry, big man.
对不起  大块头
Mavis?
梅维斯
I'm crazily scared right now.
说实话我真的很害怕
Maybe that's a good thing.
或许会很美妙呢
How could you? After I shared my pain with you?
你怎么能这样  我的血泪史白跟你讲了
- But, no... - Dad, it was just a kiss.
-但是  不  -爸爸  只是接吻而已
No, you're not allowed to kiss.
不行  不许接吻
Dad, I'm allowed to do things.
爸爸  我有我的自由
I'm not 83 anymore.
我不是八十三岁小孩了
I'm allowed to like people, or go see the world again.
我可以自由恋爱  可以去外面自由闯荡
What? You saw it!
什么  你都看见了
You said you didn't like it!
你不是很失望吗
Maybe I want to give the village another chance.
那只是第一印象而已
I just need to learn, you know,
我需要学习适应
just how to roll with it, like Johnny does.
像强尼那样  学会随机应变
No, no, you can't go to the village again.
不  不行  不许你再去那儿
Maybe you can make them see that we could be friends.
或许能让他们明白  我们可以做朋友
No, that isn't possible.
不  不可能
Well, you can't be sure. It's all in how you present yourself.
你怎么知道  这完全取决于自己的态度
No, that won't make a difference!
没用  不会有什么两样
How do you know?
你怎么知道
Because it just won't!
因为就是不会
Why? Why won't it?
为什么  为什么不会
Because that village doesn't really exist!
因为那个地方根本不存在
What do you mean "Doesn't exist"?
你说不存在是什么意思
What did you do?
你干什么了
I did what I had to do.
我做了身为父亲应该做的
What was it?
你做了什么
What exactly did you have to do? Tell me!
你到底做了什么必须做的事  告诉我
I... I built the town. The staff put it all together.
我建了那个小村  员工们一起建的
The zombies dressed up as the townspeople.
僵尸们化妆成村民
Please. I...
对不起  我...
If you really went out there and something happened to you,
如果你真的出去了  发生什么不测
I just couldn't live with myself.
我没法原谅自己
But you can live with this? Lying to me? Tricking me?
那这样就可以了吗  对我说谎  耍我
Keeping me here forever
即使知道我梦想着走出去
when you knew my dream was to go.
却仍然把我困在这里
Liar! Liar!
骗子  骗子
Oil?
要油吗
English, please.
说英语  拜托
Your voice is really annoying.
你的声音真闹心
Wait, I speak frozen.
等等  我会说冰语
He says, "Dracula has brought a human into the hotel."
他说德库拉把一个人类带进了旅社
- A human? - Stay close, Pookie!
-人类  -抱紧我  甜心
He says, "There is ze human."
他说  这里有一个人类
He has a French accent.
他有点法国口音
Johnny's not a human. He's my right arm's cousin.
强尼不是人类  他说我右手的堂弟
- He's lying. - Yeah.
-他在说谎  -对
And why is he picking his nose?
话说回来  他为什么要插自己的鼻子
He says, "It's a long story."
他说  说来话长
Hey, wait, no! Get off me!
等等  不  别缠着我
He says, "Behold ze human."
他说  亲眼所见是个人类
I don't believe it.
我不相信
Is it true? Are you a human?
真的吗  你是人类吗
Yes.
是的
I'm so sorry.
对不起
I don't care. I still want to be with you.
我不管  我还是想和你在一起
Well, tough. 'Cause I don't want to be with you.
这就难办了  因为我不想和你在一起
Because you're a monster. And I hate monsters.
因为你是怪物  而我讨厌怪物
Goodbye.
再见
Please don't hurt me!
求你别伤害我
This is all your fault!
这都是你的错
- We're getting out of here. - I'm never coming back here.
-我们要离开  -我再也不要回来了
I thought I smelt a human.
我好像闻到了人类的味道
"Human-free"? What a rip.
无人区就是个笑话
Oh. Here he comes. Count Crock-ula.
他来了  德库拉伯爵来了
I'm just glad my eyes are stitched shut,
我真庆幸眼睛被缝上了
'cause I don't even want to...
我连看都不想看...
Mavis, honey, are you in there?
梅维斯  宝贝  你在里面吗
Mavis? Mavis?
梅维斯  梅维斯
Mavis, where are you?
梅维斯  你在哪里
Mavis?
梅维斯
Dad, can you do me a favor?
爸爸  能帮我个忙吗
Yes, yes, of course, darling. Anything.
能  当然能  宝贝  帮什么忙都行
Will you erase my mind?
你能消去我的记忆吗
No, no, no, no. No, I won't do that.
不不不  我不会这么做的
There's too much I want you to remember.
有太多事情  我希望你能记住
You were right, Dad. The humans hate us.
你说得对  爸爸  人类讨厌我们
Sweetheart, there are so many eligible monsters out there.
甜心  这里多的是合适的怪物
You're so young to...
你还年轻
What is it? What are you reading?
这是什么  你在看什么
(真爱)
(118岁生日祝福)
"Two lonely bats crashed in the night.
两只寂寞的蝙蝠在夜里相遇了
"They felt a Zing. Love at first sight.
他们命中注定  一见钟情
"They knew right then they would be husband and wife.
那一刻他们就意识到他们会终成眷属
"For a Zing only happens once in your life.
一辈子只有一次命中注定的相遇
"Your Zing will come, my love.
你会遇到你的命中注定的  亲爱的
"Cherish it.
珍惜它
"Love, Mommy."
爱你的  妈妈"
I thought we Zinged, Dad.
我以为我们是命中注定  爸爸
You and Johnny?
你和强尼吗
I guess it was only me.
我猜只有我这么想
But you should be happy, Dad.
但是你应该高兴  爸爸
There's no reason for me to leave.
我再没有理由离开了
I have no more dreams. I'm just like you now.
也没有梦想了  就和你一样
(天堂)
Martha, what have I done?
玛莎  我到底做了什么
Where is my bill?
我的账单呢
- Over here. - I'm next.
-这里  -我是下一个
- I'm checking out. - Take my key! Take my key!
-我要退房  -钥匙给你  钥匙给你
What is this minibar charge?
这个小冰箱多少钱
Honey, the kids threw the minibar out the window.
亲爱的  孩子们把小冰箱丢到窗外了
- And that's our fault? - Well...
-这是我们的错吗  -这个嘛
Excuse me! Pardon, yeah.
借过  抱歉
Excuse me, I got a couple of people to express mail.
借过  有几位要寄快递
Friends, please, stop.
朋友们  拜托了  请停下来
It's too late, rat-bat!
太晚了  骗子蝙蝠
Please, I'm begging you.
求你们了  求你们了
I need you to help me find Johnny.
我需要你们帮我找到强尼
The human? He could've killed us!
那个人类吗  他会杀了我们的
He touched my guitar!
他碰了我的吉他
He put his hand in my mouth to see if it would disappear.
他把手放到我嘴里看会不会消失
He let me eat his scooter!
他让我吃了他们滑板车
I know I lied.
我是说谎了
I was wrong.
我错了
But you have to believe this:
但你们要相信
Johnny wasn't a bad guy.
强尼不是坏人
The truth is,
事实上
I don't even know if humans are bad anymore.
我都不确定人类是不是还那么邪恶
Frank, come on, buddy. You understand.
弗兰克  相信我  伙计  你明白的
He's not talking to you.
他没在跟你讲话
First you tell us humans are bad, now they're good.
你先说人类很坏  现在他们又变好了
What else? Up is down,
还有什么  颠倒是非
cold is hot, gremlins don't smell.
黑白不分  指鹿为马
I really liked Johnny, cousin or no.
我喜欢强尼  不管他是不是我堂弟
He told fun stories.
他会讲有趣的故事
I think they Zinged.
我想他们感受到了对方是自己的命中注定
They Zinged?
命中注定了吗
But I got in the way.
但我阻止了他们的感情
You only Zing once in your life.
一辈子只有一次命中注定的相遇
- Oy, now you're short-circuiting. - I don't care!
-你短路了  -无所谓
Well, what are we doing? Let's get Johnny. Come on!
还等什么呢  去找强尼吧  走吧
Yeah, let's do it! Come on!
我们走吧  一起来
Okay, okay, where am I going?
现在去哪里
The human world, before Johnny's gone forever.
去人类世界  要不强尼就回不来了
But what about the sun?
那太阳怎么办呢
I don't know. I'll just have to roll.
我不知道  但我们得行动起来
He just rolls. Rollability.
行动了  行动力啊
So we follow his boot-prints.
我们跟着他的鞋印
When they run out, that's where you come in, Wayne.
等找不到鞋印了  就靠你了  韦恩
- Me? - There!
-我吗  -那里
Yes, I knew something would fall out of that backpack.
我就知道那个背包里会有东西掉出来的
Yowch! That stinks!
臭死了
Work your magic.
快施展你的法术吧
Wait, you want me to track the smell?
等等  你要我追踪气味吗
No. My sniffing tracking days are way behind me.
不行  我的气味追踪能力早不行了
Do you know how many diapers I've changed?
你知道我换了多少块尿布了吗
How many number twos have destroyed this thing?
你知道我的鼻子被多少便便熏过了吗
But...
可是
Hey! Take it easy! Watch it!
小心点  看着路
Sit.
坐
Smell. I said smell.
闻  我说了  闻
Not me, the shirt! The shirt!
不是闻我  闻T恤  T恤
Do any of your kids still respect you?
还有听你话的孩子吗
Mm, give me a second. Oh, yeah.
让我想想  有了
Winnie! Front and center!
维尼  站到前排中间来
He got into a car. A '86 Fiat.
他上了一辆车  86年的菲亚特
It needs a little transmission work,
车子的变速器得修修了
but otherwise okay.
不过其他的还行
It drove through town to the airport. Flight 497.
车一直开过小镇去了机场  497航班
8:00 a.m. departure.
早上8点起飞
That's in 15 minutes.
还有一刻钟就要起飞了
Seat 23A.
座位号是23A
He ordered the vegetarian meal.
他点了素食餐
Okay, thank you, cutie.
好的  谢谢你  小可爱
Now, all of you, go back to your mother!
听着  都回妈妈那儿去
Sheep!
羊
High five! Don't leave me hanging.
击个掌  别让我一个人挂着嘛
- Lots of sheep! - I got this one.
-一大群羊  -这次就交给我了
What? Now there's no sheep in the road. Let's go.
怎么啦  现在没有羊挡路了  我们走
That was pretty sick, man.
真恶心  伙计
You eat lamb chops, it's the same thing.
你还吃羊排呢  不都一样吗
We don't have time for this. Come on, let's move it!
没时间争执这些了  快  我们走
Look, a human.
看  人类
Welcome to Transylvania!
欢迎来到特兰西瓦尼亚
That was trippy.
那是幻觉
Monster Festival?
怪物嘉年华
What's a Monster Festival?
怪物嘉年华是什么
(我们爱德库拉)
(高举火把  科学怪人)
Did they know we were coming?
他们知道我们要来吗
They like us?
他们喜欢我们
Really?
真的吗
Excuse me? Do you know the best way to the airport?
请问  你知道怎么去机场吗
Yes, fellow Dracula.
知道  德库拉伙计
There's only one way. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
只有一条路  不拉不拉不拉
But it's all blocked. We'll never make it in time.
但是都被堵住了  我们赶不上了
You should have left an hour earlier. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
你该提前一个小时出门  不拉不拉不拉
I do not say "Bleh, bleh-bleh."
我不说不拉不拉不拉的
All right, let's just run through it on foot.
行  我们徒步走过去吧
Drac, this'll protect you.
德库拉  这个可以保护你
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
不拉不拉不拉
Imagine if that guy knew
要是他们知道自己在跟
he was talking to the real Drac.
真德库拉说话会怎么样呢
He'd run for the hills!
会撒丫子逃跑吧
Hold it, now. Hold it, now.
等等  等等
That sounds spot on.
你说的有道理
But the only way they'd
但要想让他们知道我们真的是怪物
know the real us is if we show the real us.
我们就得露出真面目
This could work.
应该有用的
You mean, like, scare them?
你是说  吓唬他们
We haven't scared people in centuries.
我几个世纪都没吓过人了
I don't even think I have it in me anymore.
我觉得我都不会吓人了
I got nothing. I really got nothing.
我不行了  我不行了
Let's just move this along.
不如加点小道具吧
Fire! Fire!
火啊  火啊
Fire!
火啊
I'm trying to scare you!
我在吓唬你们
The real Frankenstein!
我是真的弗兰克斯坦
We know! We love you!
我们知道  我们爱你
Can you sign my torch?
可以给我的火炬签个名吗
Listen, before anything else,
听着  首先要说的是
down there's the real Dracula!
下面的那位是真的德库拉
Prove it.
拿点证据出来
All right. Continue.
好吧  继续说
Drac's daughter's in love, and he's got to get to the airport!
德库拉的女儿恋爱了  他得赶到机场去
And he can't get through this crowd!
但他没法通过拥挤的人群
Why doesn't he fly?
为什么不飞过去呢
The sun, you idiot. He's a vampire.
有太阳啊  白痴  他是吸血鬼
That's right. Thank you, Monster Nerd.
没错  谢谢你  书呆子妖怪
So, people, if you really are our friends,
如果你们真的是我们的朋友
clear a path for the man!
人们  请为他开辟一条通路吧
Okay. All Draculas, line up.
好  所有的德库拉  站好队
Bleh, bleh-bleh.
不拉不拉不拉
Everyone else, lift the capes.
其他的人  撑起斗篷
Protect our friend. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
保护我们的朋友  不拉不拉不拉
It's all for you, buddy.
这一切都是为了你  朋友
Go ahead.
去吧
Good luck! Go get 'em!
祝你好运  去找他们
Go, Drac, go!
去吧  德库拉  去吧
Go, Drac! Go, Drac!
去吧  德库拉  去吧  德库拉
Go, Drac!
去吧  德库拉
Go get 'em!
找到他们
Go, Drac, go!
去吧  德库拉  去吧
We love you, Dracula!
我们爱你  德库拉
There's no choice.
别无选择了
Okay. Okay, I must do this.
我必须做到
Jonathan. Jonathan, can you hear me?
乔纳森  乔纳森  听得到我说话吗
Tell me, do you drm of being a vampire?
告诉我  你想变成吸血鬼吗
This is how we're represented. Unbelievable.
我们居然被拍成这样  受不了
Jonathan. Jonathan.
乔纳森  乔纳森
Can you hear me?
听得到吗
Whoa! Bat!
蝙蝠
Wait, it's talking. Dracula? Is that you?
等等  他在说话  德库拉  是你吗
Huh? Dracula.
德库拉
I can't understand you.
我听不清
What? My hand's in a tan shoe?
什么  我的手在黑鞋子里
What? Japan's eating lamb stew?
什么  日本吃羊汤
Hey, do you know you're smoking?
你知道你在冒烟吗
Pardon me. Sorry, excuse me.
借过  抱歉  借过
Whoa! Excuse me.
借过
What the heck? How'd a bat get up this high?
怎么回事  蝙蝠怎么飞这么高
Folks, I'm gonna turn on the seat belt sign.
伙计们  我去把安全带指示灯打开
Just a precaution while we...
只是以防万一
While we hear a special announcement
下面请听
for my dear friend Jonathan.
我对亲爱的朋友乔纳森的特别公告
Dracula?
德库拉
My dear boy, I have made a terrible mistake.
亲爱的孩子  我犯了一个大错
I was trying to keep my baby to myself,
我想把我的宝贝留在我身边
because I knew I would always protect her.
因为我知道我会永远保护她
But I realize now,
但我现在意识到
children need to discover things for themselves.
孩子们需要自己去经历人生
They'll stumble and fall, laugh and cry,
他们会磕磕碰碰  有哭有笑
but such is life.
但这就是生活
The truth is, you and Mavis are meant to be.
事实上  你和梅维斯是天生一对
You Zinged.
你们命中注定
If she must give her trust to someone else,
如果她一定要把自己的信任交付给谁
I'm thankful that it is you, Jonathan.
我很感激那是你  乔纳森
I hope you can hear me and forgive me.
我希望你能听到这些话  原谅我
Okay, folks, we're going to make a quick turnaround to refuel,
伙计们  我们要迅速返航  加满燃料
and then we'lle back on our way.
然后再继续旅程
Quit your whining! I'm burning up out here!
少发牢骚  我在这儿都要烧着了
Dad?
爸爸
I'm fine. I'm just a little sunburnt.
我没事  只是有点晒伤
Honey,
宝贝
I always thought the worst thing ever would be seeing you go.
我一直以为看你离开是最糟糕的
But the worst is seeing you unhappy.
但事实上  看到你不开心才是最糟糕的
Mavey, I want you to live your life.
小梅  我希望你有自己的生活
I don't know how I'm supposed to do that.
我不知道要怎么做
You know, Mommy already gave you her birthday present.
妈妈已经给了你生日礼物
Can I now give you mine?
现在我把我的礼物给你吧
What do I need this for?
我还要这个包干什么呢
Oh, it comes with an accessory.
这个包还附带赠品
- You? - You.
-是你  -是你
Why are you back?
你怎么回来了
'Cause you're my Zing, Mavis.
因为你是我的命中注定  梅维斯
I'm your Zing?
我是你的命中注定吗
But you told me you hate monsters.
但是你说你讨厌怪物
Yeah, well, I was afraid your dad was gonna
那个嘛  我是怕不这么说
suck all the blood out of my body if I didn't say that.
你爸爸就会吸干我的血
I wouldn't have...
我才不会
No, he's right, I would have done that.
他说的没错  我会吸干他的血
- Dad. - I was wrong, Devil-chops.
-爸爸  -我错了  小甜心
Do you really mean it, Dad?
你是说真的吗  爸爸
Go make your own paradise.
去建造你自己的天堂吧
Can we try that kiss over again?
我们能再吻一次吗
I think we can.
可以吧
Sorry. I just... I got to get used to that.
抱歉  我只是  我得习惯这个
Go. Do your thing.
你们继续
(生日快乐  梅维斯)
Stop! Stop!
停下来  停下来
I thought I found a love but she was just a fling
我以为是真爱  结果只是暧昧
And then I met a girl and felt a different thing
然后我遇到了一个女孩  感觉大有不同
It's like you're hit in the ring Like you're pulled by a string
就像正中红心  魂牵梦萦
Can't breathe like you're choking on a chicken wing
小鹿乱撞  无法呼吸
It was a thing called a Zig and I wanted to sing
不经意间到来的爱  让我想放声歌唱
And listen to ballads of the man named Sting
听那个人的歌声  他叫斯汀
Lady looks in your eyes and it's suddenly spring
美女望向你的眼眸  好似春日降临
Like when Nala looked at Simba in The Lion King
就如狮子王里的娜娜看见辛巴
Zinging in the air and I don't have a care
空气中擦出火花  我却毫无觉察
I'm winging from the Zing that we shared
我在其中翱翔荡漾
Zinging in the rain Now I'm feeling no pain
在雨中擦出火花  痛楚都消逝不见
It's a real tie for celebrating
此刻就应欢庆
'Cause you're my Zing
因为你是我的命中注定
Drac, you ready to throw down?
德库拉  准备好来一段了吗
No, no, I just came closer to hear you better.
不不  我只是靠近点  听得更清楚
Come on, just give it a try.
来嘛  试试吧
All right, maybe just a little.
好吧  就稍微试试吧
So listen all you Zingers from here to Beijing
从这里到北京的命中注定  我们在聆听
You better crash the box spring Get ready to cling
一旦相爱  就应相守一生
'Cause if love was money you'd be yelling cha-ching
如果爱就是金钱  你就会歌唱起钱币
Next to a Zing
有了命中注定
Cupid's arrow's a little bee sting
丘比特之箭也不过蜜蜂一刺
It was a Zing and a zag and a zingidy-dee
是真爱是绝配那就是命中注定
And there was only one lady in the Zing for me
只有一位美女是我的命中注定
You better know one thing The only bling you gonna sling
你要知道  最好的珠宝
Is a wedding ring
是那婚戒
Zinging in the air
空气中满是火花
Now I don't have a care
可我毫无觉察
I'm winging from the Zing that we shared
我在其中翱翔荡漾
Zinging in the rain Now I'm feeling no pain
在雨中擦出火花  痛楚都消逝不见
It's a real time for celebrating
此刻就应欢庆
'Cause you're my Zing
因为你是我的命中注定
Feel the Zing, y'al Ba-da-bing, y'all
感受真爱  感受命中注定
Gonna knock you right out of that ring, y'l
我要把你逐出擂台
Better bring, y'all Happening, y'all
你们最好一起来  一起上
Pay attention to the undead king, y'all
都看过来  我是不死之王
I'm a monster I'm a m-monster
我是怪物  我是怪物
Housekeeping!
客房服务
I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love
我独一无二  让所有人都相爱
And I don't have to try, I just do what I does
我无需尝试  想做就做
Don't have to tell me, I already know
不用说出口  我很清楚
They all want me
他们都想要我
Yo, I run this, I smash it
是我干的  是我砸的
Like my bass real hard, boom-bastic
就像我的贝斯又重又低音
Speed race, baby, I'm a lot faster
来飙车吧  宝贝  你可没我快
Cause trouble, never listen to my master
惹是生非  从不听话
New Benz all black from Malaysia
马来西亚的全新黑奔驰
Can't drive, but my mama don't care, yup
不能开车  但妈妈也不管
To the top, I'm-a take it to the ceiling
油门踩到底  全速狂飙
I'm on the moon but I feel the sun beaming
我飞上了月球  却感到阳光闪烁
I'm so dope like ooh la So, so fly like a helicopter
我嗨倒极限乌拉拉
Sup to the hood and the homies on the block
跟邻居打招呼  朋友都在街上
Doin' it big, yeah, you know, what's up
玩就玩大的  你怎么样
Some come and try to say I'm a problem
有人想说我有问题
So crazy, gotta put 'em in an asylum
疯疯癫癫  得去精神病院
Some come and try to say I'm a problem
有人想说我有问题
Ha, solve it
看着办吧
I'm a monster, I'm a m-monster
我是怪物  我是怪物
I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love
我独一无二  让所有人相爱
And I don't have to try, I just do what I does
我无需尝试  想做就做
Don't have to tell me, I already know
不用说出口  我很清楚
They all want me
他们都想要我
I ran this, I rock this
我狂飙  我摇滚
I can see the future, no optics
我看到未来  毫无希望
More androids, robotics
更多人工智能  更多机器人
Beam up hot chicks like I'm Spock
好像斯波克船长  对着辣妞两眼发光
They be chillin' in my cockpit
他们在驾驶舱里冷静头脑
My spaceship got exotic
我的飞船古怪奇异
One be trippin', come n' whip, hypnotic
有人摔倒  鞭子快来  还有安眠药
They be talking 'bout ooh la la
他们在讲乌拉拉
Let's go far, way past them stars
我们远走天际  将星空抛在身后
We don't give a... Let's go to Mars
我才不管  去火星吧
Ay, yo I'm just trying to get it poppin'
我只想舞动起来
I wanna be the first dude to love a Martian
我想第一个爱上火星人
She'll have a maid for the swag that I'm droppin'
她得有个仆人  拾起我的舞步
I kill the game til it's chillin' in the coffin
我不会停止  除非气氛像棺材般阴冷
When I start, there ain't no stoppin'
当我开始  便再无中止
Don't be actin' like Like you didn't know
别装得好像你不知道
Like you didn't know Like you didn't know
好像你不知道  好像你不知道
Like you didn't know
好像你不知道
I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love
我独一无二  让所有人相爱
And I don't have to try, I just do what I does
我不用尝试  想做就做
Don't have to tell me, I already know
不用说出口  我很清楚
They all want me
他们都想要我
I'm one of a kind, got everybody in love
我独一无二  让所有人相爱
And I don't have to try, I just do what I does
我不用尝试  想做就做
Don't have to tell me, I already know
不用说出口  我很清楚
They all want me
他们都想要我
I'm a monster, I'm a...
我是怪物  我是
I didn't do that.
不是我干的